One hundred years ago, in the City of London, in the East-End slum of Whitechapel, a man shocked
the world by murdering, raping and mutilating five women. He was never caught.
Jack's Back is a horror, thriller, mystery film directed by Rowdy Herrington.
A young doctor is suspected when a series of Jack the
Ripper copycat killings is committed.
However, when the doctor himself is murdered, his identical twin
brother claims to have seen visions of the true killer.
John Allen Wesford / Richard Wesford, played by James Spader.
Christina "Chris" Moscari, played by Cynthia Gibb.
Sgt. Gabriel, played by Jim Haynie.
Dr. Carlos Battera, played by Robert Picardo.
Dr. Sidney Tannerson, played by Rod Loomis.
Jack Pendler, played by Rex Ryon.
Jack's Back is a 1988 American mystery thriller film written and
directed by Rowdy Herrington in his directorial debut.
It stars James Spader in dual roles, Cynthia Gibb, Jim
Haynie, Robert Picardo, Rod Loomis, and Rex Ryon.
It follows a serial killer who celebrates Jack the Ripper's
100th anniversary by committing similar murders.
The film began a limited theatrical release in the United States on May 6, 1988.
It received mixed reviews from critics, while Spader's performance was
praised and earned him a Saturn Award nomination for Best Actor.
The film explores themes of hypnosis, scalpel, dual role.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and intense.